export const inFormalQuestionBank = [
  {
    key: 1,
    question: "What is an example of Informal conversation?",
    options: [
      "Job Interviews",
      "Academic Settings",
      "Formal Meetings",
      "Friends & Families",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Friends & Families",
    explanation:
      "Informal Conversations are conversations that are often described as casual. Among the options available, Friends & Family are the only ones that can be categorised as informal Conversation",
  },

  {
    key: 2,

    question: "How would one interact when with friends?",

    options: [
      "Shout over them",
      "Interupt them",
      "Don't give them space to talk",
      "Be patient and listen",
    ],

    correctAnswer: "Be patient and listen",
    explanation:
      "Always be patient and listen to friends when interacting with them. ",
  },

  {
    key: 3,

    question:
      "What should you do when you want to speak to someone in a conversation?",

    options: [
      "Interupt the speaker",
      "Wait for the speaker to finish then politely talk to the person",
      "Yell at the speaker",
      "ignore and say your point",
    ],

    correctAnswer:
      "Wait for the speaker to finish then politely talk to the person",
    explanation:
      "Politely waiting for an opportunity to speak is always the best option. shows courtsey and can improve interactions with people",
  },

  {
    key: 4,

    question:
      "What is the main difference between talking to friends and Colleagues?",

    options: [
      "No Difference",
      "You can speak to colleagues in an unfriendly manner",
      "you can speak to friends in a causal manner while colleagues have to be formal with them",
      "You can speak to colleagues in a friendly manner but friends in an unfriendly manner",
    ],

    correctAnswer:
      "you can speak to friends in a causal manner while colleagues have to be formal with them",
    explanation:
      "Irrespective of who you are speaking to, you must always speak to them in a polite and friendly manner. Although, Formal conversations are conversations that often had with colleagues while Informal Conversations happen with Friends & Family.",
  },

  {
    key: 5,

    question:
      "In informal conversations, what is the typical level of formality used when addressing friends and family compared to addressing colleagues?",

    options: [
      "By dominating the conversation and talking more.",
      "By constantly interrupting others to share your own stories.",
      "By showing genuine interest, asking questions, and giving feedback.",
      "By showing Disinterest",
    ],

    correctAnswer:
      "By showing genuine interest, asking questions, and giving feedback.",
    explanation: "Showing Interest, asking questions and giving feedback shows genuine interaction and communication with the person you are interacting with. This makes it easier to form social bonds with the person",
  },

  {
    key: 6,

    question: "What is the role of humor in informal conversations?",

    options: [
      "Humor can lighten the mood and strengthen social bonds.",
      "It is best to avoid humor as it can lead to misunderstandings.",
      "Humor should only be used when discussing serious topics.",
      "Humour cannot be used in any situation",
    ],

    correctAnswer: "Humor can lighten the mood and strengthen social bonds.",
    explanation: "Humour when deployed correctly helps to create strong social bonds and makes it easier to interact with people",
  },

  {
    key: 7,

    question:
      "How should one handle disagreements or differing opinions in informal conversations?",

    options: [
      "Avoid discussing conflicting viewpoints to maintain harmony.",
      "Politely express your perspective and engage in a constructive dialogue.",
      "Immediately end the conversation to prevent arguments.",
      "Mock or belittle those with opposing opinions.",
    ],

    correctAnswer:
      "Politely express your perspective and engage in a constructive dialogue.",
    explanation: "Always be polite even when offended by people or having disagreements with people",
  },

  {
    key: 8,

    question:
      "What is the importance of non-verbal communication cues in informal conversations?",

    options: [
      "Non-verbal cues are irrelevant in informal conversations.",
      "They help convey emotions, understanding, and engagement.",
      "Non-verbal cues should be exaggerated to emphasize points.",
      "Non-verbal cues should be completely ignored.",
    ],

    correctAnswer: "They help convey emotions, understanding, and engagement.",
    explanation: "Non-verbal communication helps to convey information such as emotions to help build strong bonds",
  },

  {
    key: 9,

    question:
      "In informal conversations, how can you express interest in someone else point of view?",

    options: [
      "Interrupt them to share your own perspective.",
      "Ask questions to understand their viewpoint better.",
      "Nod your head and pretend to listen.",
      "Disregard their viewpoint and change the subject.",
    ],

    correctAnswer: "Ask questions to understand their viewpoint better.",
    explanation: "Asking questions shows genuine interest in a person and it helps strengthen social bonds",
  },

  {
    key: 10,

    question:
      "How do you respectfully end an informal conversation when it is time to conclude?",

    options: [
      "Abruptly stop talking and walk away.",
      "Apologize for ending the conversation and leave.",
      "Thank the participants, summarize the discussion, and express the desire to continue later.",
      "Leave without saying anything.",
    ],

    correctAnswer:
      "Thank the participants, summarize the discussion, and express the desire to continue later.",
    explanation: "Do not abruptly leave a conversation. Always express thanks to the people you are speaking to before leaving",
  },
];

export const formalQuestionBank = [
  {
    key: 1,
    question: "What is an example of formal communication?",
    options: [
      "Job Interviews",
      "Casual Gatherings",
      "Texting with Friends",
      "Family Dinners",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Job Interviews",
    explanation: "Apart from Job Interviews, all the other forms given in the options are examples of informal communication.",
  },
  {
    key: 2,
    question: "How should you address someone during a formal interview?",
    options: [
      "Use their first name",
      "Use formal titles like Mr. or Ms.",
      "Use nicknames",
      "Do not use any titles",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Use formal titles like Mr. or Ms.",
    explanation: "During formal conversations, there is a level of professionalism that has to be attained. Hence the use of formal titles like Mr and Mrs",
  },
  {
    key: 3,
    question: "What is the appropriate attire for a formal business meeting?",
    options: [
      "Casual clothing",
      "Athletic wear",
      "Business attire like suits or dresses",
      "Pajamas",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Business attire like suits or dresses",
    explanation: "During Formal meetings, professionalism has to be maintained. This includes dressing appropriately.",
  },
  {
    key: 4,
    question:
      "In formal written communication, how should you begin a letter or email?",
    options: [
      "Start with a joke",
      'Use a casual greeting like "Hey"',
      'Begin with a formal salutation like "Dear Sir/Madam"',
      "Skip the greeting and start with the message",
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Begin with a formal salutation like "Dear Sir/Madam"',
    explanation: "This formal salutation sets the tone for the communication and shows respect to the recipient. It's a conventional way to address someone in a professional or formal context, such as when writing a business letter or a formal email. Starting with a formal greeting helps establish a sense of professionalism and courtesy in your communication.",
  },

  {
    key: 5,
    question:
      "What is the primary purpose of formal written communication for example an email? ",
    options: [
      "Sharing personal stories",
      "Conveying information professionally",
      "Entertaining the reader",
      "Expressing casual thoughts",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Conveying information professionally",
    explanation: "Formal written communication is typically used in a professional context to share important information, requests, or updates in a clear and professional manner.",
  },
  {
    key: 6,
    question: "How would you address a client in a formal business email?",
    options: [
      "Use their first name",
      'Address them as "Customer"',
      "Use their last name and title",
      "Skip addressing and start with the message",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Use their last name and title",
    explanation: "This demonstrates respect and professionalism in your communication with the client.",
  },
  {
    key: 7,
    question:
      "In a formal job interview, what is the purpose of asking about your qualifications and experience?",
    options: [
      "To make you nervous",
      "To evaluate your suitability for the role",
      "To waste time",
      "To share personal stories",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "To evaluate your suitability for the role",
    explanation: " Employers ask these questions to assess whether your skills and experience align with the requirements of the job."
  },
  {
    key: 8,
    question:
      "what is a difference between formal conversation and conversation with friends",
    options: [
      "No difference",
      "Formal conversations are often professional while conversation with friends are friendly",
      "you can be rude to friends but polite to colleagues",
      "you have to be unkind to both friends and colleagues",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "Executive summary, body, conclusions, recommendations",
    explanation: "In formal conversations, you typically maintain a professional tone and adhere to certain etiquette, whereas with friends, the tone is more casual and relaxed.",
  },

  {
    key: 9,
    question: "What is the purpose of a formal business proposal?",
    options: [
      "To share personal opinions",
      "To make small talk",
      "To formally present a plan or offer",
      "To entertain the audience",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "To formally present a plan or offer",
    explanation: "Business proposals are used to outline specific plans, projects, or offers in a structured and professional manner, often with the intent of gaining approval or securing a business opportunity.",
  },
  {
    key: 10,
    question:
      "During a formal presentation, what is the role of visual aids like slides or charts?",
    options: [
      "They are unnecessary in formal presentations",
      "To confuse the audience",
      "To support and clarify key points",
      "To replace verbal communication",
    ],
    correctAnswer: "To support and clarify key points",
    explanation: "Visual aids enhance the audience's understanding by providing visual representations of information and reinforcing important concepts discussed during the presentation. They should complement, not replace, verbal communication.",
  },
];
